A Guide to the Samuel Herrick Papers, 1930-1974
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- SH numbered publications (see also listing in Box 1); numbered publications 170-231 (drafts, correspondence, reprints), 1963-1971. (Box 33)
  Grosse Annaherung des Planetoiden (1620) Geographos an die Erde. (With P. A. Thompson and P. C. Tiffany.) Orion, Der Sternenhimmel, 1969, p. 117. (See also pp. 43, 106, 112, 118, 121.)
  230
  Elements of (1566) Icarus, (1620) Geographos, (1580) Betulia, and (1685) Toro; opposition date for Geographos; close approach dates for Toro, Icarus, and Betulia. (With R. J. Reichert and P. C. Tiffany.) Ephemerides of Minor Planets, 1972, pp. 6, 9, 40-42, 54, 157, 172-175. (Leningrad, 1971.)
  231
  General relativity and the orbit of Icarus. (With I. I. Shapiro, W. B. Smith, and M. E. Ash.) Astronomical Journal, 76, No. 7, 588-606, September 1971.
- Drafts of SH articles and subject files, 1949-1973. (Box 34 & 42)
  Drafts, arranged chronologically:
  1. Coding for INA, "SH Contributions to INA," 1949.
  2. "The Nonimal System," c.1949, with correspondence re: co-development of system with E. F. Moore.
  3. Navigation, v. 3, no. 1-2, 9/12/1951 containing SH article "Inter-planetary Navigation."
  4. Drafts and revisions for SH paper "An Appraisal and Modification of Gibbs Orbit Method," 1953.
  Subject files:
  Minor planets, comets, and satellites, including asteriods (genereal information, calcuations); 1963 RH; variant orbits for Karus (1967-1968); Soviet ephemerides of minor planets (1976-1983); comet list and nots on orbits; comet 1880V.
- Drafts of articles and book chapters. (Box 35)
  1. Chapter 15, Celestial Mechanics Problems, undated but likely c. 1961.
  2. Chapter 104, DROEA 1, Differential Representation in Observational Error Analyses and Differential Correction of Orbits in Space Guidance and Space Geodesy, 3/12/1964.
  3. Astrodynamics: Part II, More Detailed Analysis, Lockheed LAC/421912, 5/1964.
  4. SH paper, "Astronomical and Astrodynamical Values of Constants and Ephemeral Data," 1965.
  5. Correspondence re: SH contribution to CRC Handbook of Tables for Mathematics, 1965-1966.
  6. "Gravitational Constants and Selection of Units," 1966.
  7. "Astrodynamics Constants Analysis," 1/1966.
  8. Drafts and manuscripts of "The Foundations of Astrodynamics," 1969, and subsequent correspondence.
  9. Working papers and final manuscript for "Accuracy of Ageton's Method" (for determining position at sea/air).
  10. Two draft chapters of EU Condon Handbook of Physics.
  11. Correspondence with Chemical Rubber Co. re: Critical Reviews Journal.
  12. Notes re: reviews of Einstein books "Theory of Relativity" and "The Principle of Relativity."
  13. Working papers and final manuscript, "The Determination of Position from a Photographic Plate."
  14. Reprint, "The Step by Step Integration of x=f(x, y, z, t) without a 'Corrector.'"
  15. Folder of worksheets for "Dr. Herrick Problem #1, Elliptic" and instruction sheet for Naval Observatory on "Herrick's Table."
  16. Drafts and outlines re: perturbations, two-centers, fly-by, centers of attraction, and combination of orbits.
- Subject files. (Box 36)
  Computers and electronic calculations, including differential analyzer operation and problems (c. 1947); manuals on early computers, including EDVAC and ZEPHYR (1947-1949); Monroe Calculator; SWAC memoranda, coding sheets; Tezak inventory of tapes (1964).
- Subject files. (Box 37)
  Mathematical techniques, including manuscript on polynominal expansions; Hansen's method of general perturbations; data smoothing; numberical methods; quasilinerization; Fisher ellipsoid; new origin; Jeff projects; propogation of gravity; abberations; bulge perturbations; Hamiltonian-Goldreich rectilinear perturbation problem; general perturbations; combination of orbits; center of attraction; two stationary centers.
- Subject files. (Box 38)
  Mathematical techniques, including units and constants; smoothing; universal variables.
- Subject files. (Box 39)
  Minor planets, comets, and satellites, including Minor Planet Center (MPC) notices 151-2800 (1944-1967); USSR publication on the ephemerides of minor planets (1950-1967).
- Subject files. (Box 40)
  Minor planets, comets, and satellites, including Betulia (numerical integrations, plate reductions, indirect perturbation terms); Gary Smith predictions of orbits for Toro, Icarus, Betulia, and Geographos (1973); Geographos (early Enke orbit, ephemerides, ellipse graphs, plate measures) (c.1967-1970); Icarus (c. 1969-1971).
- Subject files. (Box 41)
  Minor planets, comets, and satellites, including minor planet Lanzia; JIX adn JXII ephmerides (1949-1971); 1953 EA emphemerides calculations; photos of Betulia and Icarus (1961); 1957 MK Trojan orbits of N7-C13; (1580) Betulia; Observations unrepresented (1946-1948); notes and calculations on orbvits and minor planets; correspondence and reprints re: Toro, Icarus, Geographos (1972); 1968 calculations and MPC's on Betulia.
- Subject files. (Box 43)
  Minor planets, comets, and satellites, including MPS 68 and 72 series of folders on Icarus, Betulia, Toro, 1957MK, 1953EA, 1950DA, Alpha I 1959, 1948EA, Hoffmeister object HAC 1495, 1963 RH.
- Manuscript calculations. (Box 44)
  Ellips graphs 1566. 1580, 1620; calculations ephemeris 1948 EA; 1968 ephemeris of 1568 Icarus; projects--potential; minor planet criteria; Trojans; Tauri; Uranus V=Miranda; 1235 Shorria; Armida (514); planetary coordinates; Halley's comet.
- Manuscript calculations. (Box 45)
  Shock waves of Icarus calculations; geophysical constants and correction methods; Project 15; ephemeral calculations A=1, A=5, and A=25; ephemeral calcuations OSP16; Prob 1--elliptic; Icarus calculations, including Mercury perturbations.
- Manuscript calculations. (Box 46 & Duplicates)
  Ephemeral calculations unknown object, labelled "Project 2"; ephemeral calculations "Project 3--General Perturbations"; ephemeral calcuations Spec. Pert. Rocket to Venus, RV; Sperm 1 calculations and collection of formulae (Elster and Mace).
- Computer printouts. (Box 47)
  Early SH printouts; rectilinear calculations; "Herrick's Fable"; coordinates of Venus and Jupiter; first and second differences Sun's and four inner planets' attraction to Jupiter; sin x and cos x with first and second differences to 15 decimal places; 1966 fly-by of 1948EA.
- Computer printouts. (Box 48)
  Computer runs on Betulia (1969); computer runs testing Gauss integration versus four cycle R-K 1.73.
- Computer printouts. (Box 49)
  Gary R. Smith, two-body problems and Betulia ephemeris, runs 255, 257, 260,, 266, 272, 273, 331, 334, 369-372, 375, 377, 380-382, two unnumbered; Mercury-related ephemeris of Icarus 1968, June 1968.
- Computer printouts, 1968-1973. (Box 50)
  Gary R. Smith, 7/68-9/73 Betulia ephemeris.
- Computer printouts, 1971-1972. (Box 51)
  Printout and coding sheets: Kepler cubic convergence, Betulia, Geographos, Toro, Icarus ephemerides with earth perturbations, 8/71-4-72.
- Computer printouts, 1972-1973. (Box 52)
  Printout and coding sheets: G. R. Smith, 4/72-4/73; Herrick direct rendezvous and miscellaneous minor planets.
- Computer printouts, 1966-1968. (Box 53)
  Icarus, 1966-1968.
- Computer printouts. (Box 54)
  Geographos 1970 (G. R. Smith); R-K ohr e 0.1, 0.5, 0.9; 1963 RH Bullock; 1965 BA Bullock; Icarus 1965 II; Icarus 1968 encounter.
- Computer printouts, 1970-1973. (Box 55)
  G. R. Smith computer runs (3/73); 10/70-1/71 computer runs MER 545 RBR SVD MAT.
- Computer printouts, 1971-1973. (Box 56)
  Two-body rendezvous (9/71); hard copy of URSA HELP (12/72); miscellaneous runs (1972-1973).
- Computer printouts, 1968-1973. (Box 57)
  Planetary coordinates (1968); Icarus calculations (six-day trial, 1967); Betulia ephemeris (8/72); Geographos (4/73).
- Computer printouts, 1973. (Box 58)
  G. R. Smith computer listings and runs 200-231 ("200" labelled "12n=-1.00 to 0.48 1/2n=.0," 3/73).
- Computer printouts, 1971-1973. (Box 59)
  G. R. Smith computer listings and runs 330, 344, 374-378 two-body 180 degree rendezvous, GEOTAP (4/73-3/71); G. R. Smith runs, all labelled "Herrick inversal method, 133 cases."
- Computer printouts, 1973. (Box 60)
  G. R. Smith computer listings and runs labelled "290" through "345" (4/73), including "Geo. close approach: Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune" and "180 degree rendezvous--Herrick Dir. Method: Force Orbit Plane."
- Computer printouts, 1971-1974. (Box 61)
  R. G. Totten programs (Icarus two-day ephemeris); 1965 Icarus two-day ephemeris (Ford); 1965 Geographos two-day ephemeris (Ford); 1965 Toro (1948OA) two-day ephemeris (Ford); series of runs by G. R. Smith (1971-1974).
- Subject files. (Box 62)
  Miscellaneous computer card decks and runs.
- Subject files. (Box 63)
  Space exploration, including space colonies; simplified version of a rocket; UCLA moon base study; outline on space technology for use in articles, etc.; space navigation (instruments. PLG patent, Apollo navigation); "Some chapters for Rocket Navigation"; Astronautical engineering handbook; proposals for interplanetary trajectory study; high-precision orbit determination; Project Mercury; interplanetary navigation.
- Subject files. (Box 64 & 67)
  Space exploration, including reprints, notes, and correspondence on artficial satellites.
- Card files (4) with names and addresses, bibliographies for celestial mechanics and astrodynamics. (Box 65)
- Drawings and calculations. (Oversize Folder 1)